Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 28.
We will continue with recursion and we are asked to explain the functionality of the following function.
So we have this class, hello, and we have to function the main and the function.
Fun.
Okay.
This is the function.
The same writing, ninety nine percent with a C and in Python, we some semtex will be different, but
I use Java and C more because the data structures and algorithms in all universities are taught in and
teach by that Java and C courses languages.
OK, so both the video and think about this recursion methods.
What is the result of this recursion?
What we are going, what we are trying and what we are going to calculate in this function?
Fine.
So I hope you use and use your paper and pen and.
You comment below on all of your solutions to our exercises in order to make discussion about exercises
and where if you have any thing that it is doubt we can clarify.
So first of all, we start in the main.
The main is system without the brand.
We are printing the function and passing for three as parameters.
So.
We are calling this function function.
Fun, but we have here the function F.
Function containing Ford and the city, so A is for and B is three.
OK.
This is the function.
Now let's see if B equal equal to zero.
B equal equal to zero.
No.
So we are skipping this case.
If be modular two equal equal to zero three.
Modular two is not equal to zero because three modular two is equal to one.
OK.
Otherwise, so we have skipped this block, this block, and we are going to execute this code because
function return function a times a, which is a square.
Be over to.
Times a day, you see, guys, this function, we are calling this function times, so function for
three will call a function.
Another function by recurs recursively by passing a square, a square, which is 16.
And be over to which is won because B is an integer three, over two is 1.5 1.5.
The point five the decimal part of it, we we will remove it because B is an integer and it is not a
double or float.
OK, so we are passing function 16 16 as a and B is one times a, but I told you that in recursive or
recursion, we need to execute this method, this function before, before timing and multiplying it
with a.
So we need to get a result of this function to multiply with a and then returning back to the function
for three as parameters.
So.
16 one.
Try if be equal, equal to zero.
No, it will return one.
No, that's not the case.
If be a modular two, equal equal to zero.
No, it is not the case.
OK, guys.
It's not the case.
So return function again.
16 times 16.
And be over two one over to a 0.5 and B is integer, so we need to pass B as zero times A.
OK.
16 times 16.
Two five six.
OK, now we are calling the function again by passing as 256 and zero as B.
OK, so this function f be equal to equal.
Equal to zero.
Yes.
So return one.
OK.
So this function is now executing this block.
So function passing to five, six and B as zero will return one.
So this is that one.
Now we are going back through this course of executing the functions.
This function has been calculated at this equal to one, so we are going back.
So this is the recursion.
We have seen it before in the previous videos, and we have seen that the recursion needs to calculate
a value and then substitute it back at the upper two upper values.
So one is substituting this function times A, which is 16.
So the this function would result in one times 16.
OK.
One time, 16 is equal to 16.
This function will replace this, so function 16 one times a.
Sorry, 200, sorry, sorry.
This is.
Not the case.
There's.
Yes, yes.
So this through.
I have missed this.
It's 16.
One times 16 equal to 16, this has been replaced here now here is 16 is a square, so a is equal to
four.
Okay.
So 16 is replacing this function.
OK.
Time is a.
A is equal to four in this case, so 16 times four is equal to sixty four.
32 plus 32 as equal to 64 again, going up and maintaining that sixty four as the result of the function
containing.
For as a and B, as three.
So this is the result.
OK, now how what is the relation between this?
Why function if we pass a as four and three as B, it will give us like this result?
OK.
Think about that.
What is the relation between four and three that will give us 64?
Think about it, guys.
For.
Plus, the three, seven, No.
Four three, Reno, four times three.
No, this is not the case.
12 for.
Power three.
Yes, it is equal to 64, so for.
Sorry.
Let me put it in, so for.
Power three.
Is equal to 64.
So this is the case we are calculating and this function A to power B.
So this is the solution.
You see, guys, how we get the solution, how to work with recursion.
How recursion works.
And how the pattern of recursion and solving recursion exercises you should follow.
This is very important.
And I need.